[Music] button
[Music] Professor Dave and Chegg here we've
learned a lot about proton NMR Spectra and this
is indeed the single most important technique in
organic chemistry for the characterization of any
molecule however there are other related tools
that can also be quite useful and one of them
is carbon 13 NMR spectroscopy let's learn how
this works as well as another form of nuclear
magnetic resonance spectroscopy this operates by
precisely the same principles as proton NMR it is
simply focused on a different nuclide instead
of protium an isotope of hydrogen data will be
collected regarding carbon 13 nuclides now it
is true that only about one percent of carbon
atoms will be carbon 13 Isotopes so most of
the individual molecules in a sample will
not contain any carbon 13. but this is okay
because given a macroscopic sample trillions
upon trillions of molecules within that sample
will contain a carbon 13 atom at a particular
location in the molecule thus generating data
for us to examine regarding that position on the
molecule and the same goes for every other carbon
in the molecule so we can therefore gather data
regarding the chemical environment experienced
by every carbon atom in any structure this
approach can be described as signal averaging
as performed by Fourier transform NMR or ft NMR
the tricky thing about signal averaging is that
there is a lot of noise to deal with the signals
from the 13c nuclides are weak in comparison
to background electronic noise but we can run
hundreds or even thousands of Trials and average
them together hence the term signal averaging and
digitally lock on to any data that is non-random
and therefore due to 13c nuclides the random noise
can then be minimized so that the important data
can stand out the problem is that taking so many
measurements is extremely time consuming that's
where the Ft NMR comes into play a short pulse
of RF energy irradiates the sample all 1H and
13c nuclides resonate at once and the resulting
complex signal is manipulated using Fourier
transforms allowing for data to be collected
in mere seconds we will examine carbon 13 Spectra
later but for now there is one interesting fact
to be aware of we will not see splitting patterns
the way we do with proton NMR the reason for this
has to do with the low abundance of this isotope
it is unlikely that carbon 13 nuclides will be
adjacent in any particular molecule so there is
no opportunity for them to split each other's
signals the way protons do coupling with protons
themselves also does not occur because these
Spectra are recorded with Broadband decoupling a
second irradiation makes hydrogen's spin flip so
rapidly that their local magnetic fields average
to zero and no coupling with carbon will occur
so with that we understand roughly
how carbon 13 NMR Works through
signal averaging and Fourier transforms
Professor day for Chegg see you next time